<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mirko Caserta</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/</link><description>Recent content on Mirko Caserta</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mirkocaserta.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🇺🇸 Ballads</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/10/ballads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/10/ballads/</guid><description>«You can play a shoestring if you&amp;rsquo;re sincere.» — John Coltrane
I have been playing the piano since I was a little kid. Actually, I played the organ first, as my dad had a transistor one that was pretty state of the art for the time (I was born in 1974 so you get the idea).
Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing keyboards since forever and I&amp;rsquo;ve also picked up different instruments over the years, probably too many of them as I never really mastered one.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 The Last Time I Had Fun</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/10/the-last-time-i-had-fun/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/10/the-last-time-i-had-fun/</guid><description>«Everything I’ve ever let go of has claw marks on it.» — David Foster Wallace
The nice thing with instrumental music is that giving titles to songs is maybe trivial and can sometimes be lots of fun.
I had this album&amp;rsquo;s title written down in a list of possible song names that I keep in my notebook. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really thinking about it until I started seeing the album cover showing up online after I pushed the publish button.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Ear Candy</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/07/ear-candy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/07/ear-candy/</guid><description>«There&amp;rsquo;s nothing remarkable about it. All one has to do is hit the right keys at the right time and the instrument plays itself.» — J. S. Bach
What I find amusing about quotes is that it&amp;rsquo;s very hard to find out if they are trustworthy. I like to think that the Kapellmeister might actually have said that. It&amp;rsquo;s quite plausible I think.
Bach wrote music for the glory of his god and for the refreshment of the spirit.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Until Further Notice</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/03/until-further-notice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2022/03/until-further-notice/</guid><description>«What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with feeling nostalgic? It&amp;rsquo;s the only distraction left for those who have no faith in the future.» — &amp;ldquo;The Great Beauty&amp;rdquo; (2013, Paolo Sorrentino)
When I was a kid, music came on vinyl. I loved it for the beautiful covers but most of all for the amount of details you could find on them. Most music labels would report lots of interesting stuff such as the performers&amp;rsquo; names and the instruments they played.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Bruce: cryptography in Java made easy</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/bruce-cryptography-in-java-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/bruce-cryptography-in-java-made-easy/</guid><description>I just released Bruce, a Java library for performing cryptography.
Here are the relevant links:
github docs download There still is much room for improvement.
If you are new to open source Java library development, a good place to start is taking a look at the open issues. Most of them are pretty easy.
I hope you find this useful. I certainly have in my daily work.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Anxiety Driven Development</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/anxiety-driven-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 10:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/anxiety-driven-development/</guid><description>As a software developer, you will always find yourself in times when someone is putting an abysmal amount of pressure on you to complete something.
This is normal and not something under your control. Accept this is how every job works and take it for granted as the oxygen in the air you breathe.
Can this be avoided? If you have an enlightened project manager/team leader/whatever, she won&amp;rsquo;t put any pressure on you.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 The Matrix Screensaver for Commodore 64, version 2</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64-version-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64-version-2/</guid><description>After trying to implement the digital rain algorithm in 6502 assembly and failing miserably, I decided to try the cc65 toolkit and write some C code.
It takes a while to load but what you are seeing above is a live emulation of the screensaver software.
Once it&amp;rsquo;s loaded, the following commands are available through the keyboard:
key use A amber mode B binary mode D dna mode F full charset mode (default) G green mode (default) H hex mode L lgbtq mode Q quit You can take a look at the source code in my C64 Playground repository on github and download the prg image for your retro emulation enjoyment.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 The Matrix Screensaver for Commodore 64</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64/</guid><description>I am trying to learn some 6502 assembly and this is the result of one of my first experiments.
It takes a while to load but what you are seeing above is a live emulation of my screensaver software.
Once it&amp;rsquo;s loaded, the following commands are available through the keyboard:
key use B binary display mode X hex display mode R random display mode (default) N increments border color M increments background color Q quit You can take a look at the source code in my C64 Playground repository on github and download the D64 image for your retro emulation enjoyment.</description></item><item><title>🇮🇹 Esempio di Time Series Data e CompletableFuture in Java</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/02/esempio-di-time-series-data-e-completablefuture-in-java/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 08:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/02/esempio-di-time-series-data-e-completablefuture-in-java/</guid><description>Esempio di Time Series Data e CompletableFuture in Java Il codice completo di tutti gli esempi si trova qui.
Come lanciare il programma mvn clean compile verify exec:java Prefazione Supponiamo di voler calcolare un indice di qualità dell&amp;rsquo;aria basato su due valori:
temperatura dell&amp;rsquo;aria percentuale di monossido di carbonio nell&amp;rsquo;aria Dati i seguenti simboli:
simbolo significato AQi indice di qualità dell&amp;rsquo;aria T temperatura dell&amp;rsquo;aria in gradi Celsius Tm temperatura massima dell&amp;rsquo;aria in C° C percentuale di monossido di carbonio nell&amp;rsquo;aria Possiamo calcolare l&amp;rsquo;AQi con questa specie di formula:</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Time Series Data and CompletableFuture example in Java</title><link>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/02/time-series-data-and-completablefuture-example-in-java/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mirkocaserta.com/posts/2021/02/time-series-data-and-completablefuture-example-in-java/</guid><description>Time Series Data and CompletableFuture example in Java Full code for all the examples can be found here.
How to run the program mvn clean compile verify exec:java Preface Suppose we want to calculate an air quality index based on two values:
air temperature percentage of carbon monoxide in the air Given the following symbols:
symbol meaning AQi air quality index T air temperature in Celsius degrees Tm maximum air temperature in C° C percentage of carbon monoxide in the air We may calculate the AQi with the following sorry excuse of a formula:</description></item></channel></rss>