<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software development on</title><link>/categories/software-development/</link><description>Recent content in software development on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🇺🇸 Posting to Mastodon</title><link>/posts/2022/12/posting-to-mastodon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/12/posting-to-mastodon/</guid><description>Since the latest twitter issues due to Space Karen, I got myself a Mastodon account and I must say that, so far, the experience has been extremely positive, possibly due to the fact that most of the people I follow are well behaved nerds who care about sharing good vibes. If you also feel like joining, please take a look at Join Mastodon and see for yourself.
Anyway, I found myself pretty soon in the need to automate my posts.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Bruce: cryptography in Java made easy</title><link>/posts/2021/05/bruce-cryptography-in-java-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021/05/bruce-cryptography-in-java-made-easy/</guid><description>I just released Bruce, a Java library for performing cryptography.
Here are the relevant links:
github docs download There still is much room for improvement.
If you are new to open source Java library development, a good place to start is taking a look at the open issues. Most of them are pretty easy.
I hope you find this useful. I certainly have in my daily work.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Anxiety Driven Development</title><link>/posts/2021/05/anxiety-driven-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 10:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021/05/anxiety-driven-development/</guid><description>As a software developer, you will always find yourself in times when someone is putting an abysmal amount of pressure on you to complete something.
This is normal and not something under your control. Accept this is how every job works and take it for granted as the oxygen in the air you breathe.
Can this be avoided? If you have an enlightened project manager/team leader/whatever, she won&amp;rsquo;t put any pressure on you.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 The Matrix Screensaver for Commodore 64, version 2</title><link>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64-version-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64-version-2/</guid><description>After trying to implement the digital rain algorithm in 6502 assembly and failing miserably, I decided to try the cc65 toolkit and write some C code.
It takes a while to load but what you are seeing above is a live emulation of the screensaver software.
Once it&amp;rsquo;s loaded, the following commands are available through the keyboard:
key use A amber mode B binary mode D dna mode F full charset mode (default) G green mode (default) H hex mode L lgbtq mode Q quit You can take a look at the source code in my C64 Playground repository on github and download the prg image for your retro emulation enjoyment.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 The Matrix Screensaver for Commodore 64</title><link>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64/</guid><description>I am trying to learn some 6502 assembly and this is the result of one of my first experiments.
It takes a while to load but what you are seeing above is a live emulation of my screensaver software.
Once it&amp;rsquo;s loaded, the following commands are available through the keyboard:
key use B binary display mode X hex display mode R random display mode (default) N increments border color M increments background color Q quit You can take a look at the source code in my C64 Playground repository on github and download the D64 image for your retro emulation enjoyment.</description></item><item><title>🇮🇹 Esempio di Time Series Data e CompletableFuture in Java</title><link>/posts/2021/02/esempio-di-time-series-data-e-completablefuture-in-java/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 08:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021/02/esempio-di-time-series-data-e-completablefuture-in-java/</guid><description>Esempio di Time Series Data e CompletableFuture in Java Il codice completo di tutti gli esempi si trova qui.
Come lanciare il programma mvn clean compile verify exec:java Prefazione Supponiamo di voler calcolare un indice di qualità dell&amp;rsquo;aria basato su due valori:
temperatura dell&amp;rsquo;aria percentuale di monossido di carbonio nell&amp;rsquo;aria Dati i seguenti simboli:
simbolo significato AQi indice di qualità dell&amp;rsquo;aria T temperatura dell&amp;rsquo;aria in gradi Celsius Tm temperatura massima dell&amp;rsquo;aria in C° C percentuale di monossido di carbonio nell&amp;rsquo;aria Possiamo calcolare l&amp;rsquo;AQi con questa specie di formula:</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Time Series Data and CompletableFuture example in Java</title><link>/posts/2021/02/time-series-data-and-completablefuture-example-in-java/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021/02/time-series-data-and-completablefuture-example-in-java/</guid><description>Time Series Data and CompletableFuture example in Java Full code for all the examples can be found here.
How to run the program mvn clean compile verify exec:java Preface Suppose we want to calculate an air quality index based on two values:
air temperature percentage of carbon monoxide in the air Given the following symbols:
symbol meaning AQi air quality index T air temperature in Celsius degrees Tm maximum air temperature in C° C percentage of carbon monoxide in the air We may calculate the AQi with the following sorry excuse of a formula:</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 An Introduction to Time Representation, Serialization and Management in Software</title><link>/posts/2013/04/an-introduction-to-time-representation-serialization-and-management-in-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013/04/an-introduction-to-time-representation-serialization-and-management-in-software/</guid><description>Most issues in software development usually arise from poor, inconsistent knowledge of the domain at hand. A topic apparently as simple as time representation, serialization and management can easily cause a number of problems both to the neophyte and to the experienced programmer.
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll see that there&amp;rsquo;s no need to be a Time Lord to grasp the very simple few concepts needed not to incur into time management hell.</description></item><item><title>🇮🇹 Scrivi messaggi di log decenti, altrimenti Gesù piange</title><link>/posts/2009/10/scrivi-messaggi-di-log-decenti-altrimenti-ges%C3%B9-piange/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2009/10/scrivi-messaggi-di-log-decenti-altrimenti-ges%C3%B9-piange/</guid><description>Vorrei proporre alcune considerazioni sulla apparentemente oscura arte dello scrivere messaggi di log. Dico apparentemente oscura perché si tratta di un argomento apparentemente banale ma che in realtà si rivela complesso.
Trattandosi di osservazioni generali, queste andrebbero prese con una dose di buon senso e sotto stretta osservazione del proctologo di fiducia; ciò non toglie che con ogni probabilità troverai le seguenti note ragionevolmente utili poiché basate sull’esperienza personale (a.k.a. sangue versato sul campo).</description></item></channel></rss>