<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on</title><link>/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🇺🇸 Ballads</title><link>/posts/2022/10/ballads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/10/ballads/</guid><description>«You can play a shoestring if you&amp;rsquo;re sincere.» — John Coltrane
I have been playing the piano since I was a little kid. Actually, I played the organ first, as my dad had a transistor one that was pretty state of the art for the time (I was born in 1974 so you get the idea).
Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing keyboards since forever and I&amp;rsquo;ve also picked up different instruments over the years, probably too many of them as I never really mastered one.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 The Last Time I Had Fun</title><link>/posts/2022/10/the-last-time-i-had-fun/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/10/the-last-time-i-had-fun/</guid><description>«Everything I’ve ever let go of has claw marks on it.» — David Foster Wallace
The nice thing with instrumental music is that giving titles to songs is maybe trivial and can sometimes be lots of fun.
I had this album&amp;rsquo;s title written down in a list of possible song names that I keep in my notebook. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really thinking about it until I started seeing the album cover showing up online after I pushed the publish button.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Ear Candy</title><link>/posts/2022/07/ear-candy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/07/ear-candy/</guid><description>«There&amp;rsquo;s nothing remarkable about it. All one has to do is hit the right keys at the right time and the instrument plays itself.» — J. S. Bach
What I find amusing about quotes is that it&amp;rsquo;s very hard to find out if they are trustworthy. I like to think that the Kapellmeister might actually have said that. It&amp;rsquo;s quite plausible I think.
Bach wrote music for the glory of his god and for the refreshment of the spirit.</description></item><item><title>🇺🇸 Until Further Notice</title><link>/posts/2022/03/until-further-notice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022/03/until-further-notice/</guid><description>«What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with feeling nostalgic? It&amp;rsquo;s the only distraction left for those who have no faith in the future.» — &amp;ldquo;The Great Beauty&amp;rdquo; (2013, Paolo Sorrentino)
When I was a kid, music came on vinyl. I loved it for the beautiful covers but most of all for the amount of details you could find on them. Most music labels would report lots of interesting stuff such as the performers&amp;rsquo; names and the instruments they played.</description></item></channel></rss>