<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C64 on </title>
    <link>/tags/c64/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C64 on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/c64/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>🇺🇸 The Matrix Screensaver for Commodore 64, version 2</title>
      <link>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64-version-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64-version-2/</guid>
      <description>After trying to implement the digital rain algorithm in 6502 assembly and failing miserably, I decided to try the cc65 toolkit and write some C code.&#xA;It takes a while to load but what you are seeing above is a live emulation of the screensaver software.&#xA;Once it&amp;rsquo;s loaded, the following commands are available through the keyboard:&#xA;key use A amber mode B binary mode D dna mode F full charset mode (default) G green mode (default) H hex mode L lgbtq mode Q quit You can take a look at the source code in my C64 Playground repository on github and download the prg image for your retro emulation enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🇺🇸 The Matrix Screensaver for Commodore 64</title>
      <link>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2021/05/the-matrix-screensaver-for-commodore-64/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to learn some 6502 assembly and this is the result of one of my first experiments.&#xA;It takes a while to load but what you are seeing above is a live emulation of my screensaver software.&#xA;Once it&amp;rsquo;s loaded, the following commands are available through the keyboard:&#xA;key use B binary display mode X hex display mode R random display mode (default) N increments border color M increments background color Q quit You can take a look at the source code in my C64 Playground repository on github and download the D64 image for your retro emulation enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
